# **Kevan Ahlquist**

920 Delaware St. SE Apt. 3028, Minneapolis, MN 55414 | (320) 583-5412 | ahlqu039@umn.edu

## **Professional Summary**

Software engineering with focus on user experience. Recent experience in designing, implementing, and deploying web apps with Python, hardening existing code to eliminate security vulnerabilities, and optimizing project workflows. Projects include a web app for event scheduling (Python, github.com/kevana/ummbNet), a web app for code review to encourage good development practices (Javascript), an automated antenna positioning system (C), and porting a DMX receiver from ASM to C (github.com/teslaworksumn/HeadMaster). Familiar with git, svn, TFS usage and best practices.

#### **Technical Skills**

Programming Languages	Python, HTML, SQL, JavaScript, CSS, C/C++, Java,
	Assembly, shell scripting
Systems / Platforms	Windows XP/Vista/7/8, Server 2008, OS X, Linux (Debian,
	Ubuntu)
Software / Tools	git, svn, TFS, Visual Studio, Office, ssh, gdb, diff tools,
	Apache, nginx, uwsgi, Flask, SQLAlchemy
Concepts	Secure SQL design, Python web development, REST, OOP,
	ORM, Unix systems programming, TCP/UDP networking,
	threading, relational database modeling

### **Education**

University of Minnesota

Minneapolis, Minnesota

Spring 2014

College of Science and Engineering Bachelor of Science Major: Computer Science

GPA: 3.60

## Job History

Open Access Technology International (OATI)

Minneapolis, MN

Jr. Software Developer Intern (SQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript, C#)

Oct. 2013 - Feb. 2014

OATI is a software-as-a-service provider for the energy industry, providing transmission management, trading, and compliance systems.

- Designed and implemented code review web app for company-wide use (Javascript)
- Refactored SQL procedures to eliminate security vulnerabilities and improve performance
- Performed peer code reviews daily to reinforce development best practices
- Converted existing applications from proprietary scripting language to ASP.NET framework

Superior Access Solutions (SAS)

Lakeville, MN

Software Developer Intern (C/C++, Python)

Jan. 2013 - Oct. 2013

SAS is a small systems integrator that specializes in networking and video transmission solutions

- Designed a tool to stress test and monitor the health of network segments carrying video broadcast streams (RTP protocol, Python, C)
- Created a KLV metadata generator with C for use in unmanned aviation systems
- Implemented **driver features** for automated antenna positioning system (C)

University of Minnesota 1-HELP

Minneapolis, MN

Technology Support Representative – **Student Employee Leadership Program** 

Aug. 2010 - Nov. 2013

- Utilized effective communication skills to quickly resolve customer issues
- Created documentation and guides for systems used by 50,000+ people
- Trained new employees on customer service best practices and efficient troubleshooting

### **Other Activities**

University of Minnesota Bands – Lead trumpet	2010 - 2014
Bluecoats Drum and Bugle Corps – Lead trumpet, equipment manager	2012 - 2013
Boy Scouts of America – Eagle Scout, Jr. Assistant Scoutmaster	2003 - 2011